# RAPHAELLA D'ALESSANDRO

## **EDUCATION**

### Makers Academy (April 2022 – August 2022)

• Full stack software engineering bootcamp focusing on OOP, TDD, agile methodologies, Ruby, JavaScript, pair programming and group work.

## SheCodes (May 2021 - August 2021)

- Series of front-end web development courses: Basics, Plus, Responsive, and React.
- Focusing on responsive web design, flexbox, SEO, API, hosting, GitHub, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React

## Richmond Upon Thames College (2016 - 2018)

• Level 3 Health & Social Care BTEC - Distinction\*, Distinction\*, Distinction

## **University of West London (2016)**

• Musical Theatre Grade 8 – Distinction

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### January 2020 - June 2021

#### Administrator - Talent & People • Havas Life Medicom

- Creating reports for absence, compliance and objectives allowed me to refine my attention to detail.
- I took on the additional responsibility of becoming a Diversity & Inclusion Ambassador. This included writing pieces for internal website focusing on LGBTQ+ issues.
- Most of my time was spent on the recruitment & onboarding process, I took new starters on their
  journey from screening candidates to running induction sessions. Time management when balancing
  several new starters at once, along with attention to detail required for writing contracts and
  arranging interviews were key skills I developed here.

#### May 2019 – October 2019

## Receptionist • Kingston Lodge Hotel & Bingham Riverhouse

- In this customer facing role I used my interpersonal communication skills to greet & interact with guests during their stay, making sure their experience was friendly and seamless.
- Having the responsibility of training new team members was something I enjoyed. It allowed me to develop my leadership skills as well as my active listening skills.
- Balancing and reconciling PDQ transactions against the system for the reception, bar and restaurant assisted me in polishing my problem-solving skills and meticulous eye for detail.

#### October 2018 - April 2019

#### Administration & Social Media Marketing • Various West End Producers

- Growing follower count and engagement on multiple platforms incl. Twitter & Instagram required analytical skills and creativity.
- Managing inboxes, updating websites, and responding to enquiries allowed me to practice my communication skills and time management.
- Event planning & marketing was the perfect opportunity to put into practice project management skills I started developing during my entrepreneurship while I was at school.

## **ABOUT ME**

My work background has been people facing roles that focus heavily on communication; whereas in my free time I prefer to do less talking, spending it reading, playing video games, and seeing musical theatre shows. I explored a lot of different roles since leaving college and took my favourite things from each of them when I left:

- creativity
- structure
- fast-paced work
- space for learning new things

I found all of this in software engineering. I chose coding because it is an outlet for creativity that I have not found in previous roles, as well as being intellectually challenging. I love the problemsolving aspect as it keeps me motivated and energetic.



South West London





I worked in hospitality roles whilst still in full-time education which helped me develop my communication, problem solving and most importantly time management skills further